<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<example>
    <name>Advanced Threading</name>
    <category>Advanced</category>
    <sourceFile>src/07_advanced_threading/advanced_threading_hip.hip</sourceFile>
    <description>
        <title>Advanced Threading 🧵🤝 - Orchestra of Synchronized GPU Cooperation</title>
        <overview>
            This example demonstrates sophisticated thread cooperation and synchronization patterns 
            that enable thousands of GPU threads to work together safely and efficiently. Like 
            conducting a symphony orchestra where musicians must perfectly coordinate their timing, 
            advanced threading shows how GPU threads can share data, synchronize actions, and 
            coordinate complex multi-stage algorithms without conflicts or race conditions.
        </overview>
        <analogy>
            <strong>Think of it like this:</strong> Imagine coordinating a massive kitchen with 1000 chefs 
            preparing a complex meal. Some chefs prepare ingredients (producers), others cook dishes (consumers), 
            and everyone must coordinate perfectly - no chef can start the sauce until ingredients are ready, 
            and all dishes must finish simultaneously. Advanced threading provides the coordination 
            mechanisms that make this chaotic potential into harmonious cooperation.
        </analogy>
        <features>
            <feature><strong>Producer-Consumer Patterns:</strong> Threads safely share data through sophisticated coordination</feature>
            <feature><strong>Barrier Synchronization:</strong> Ensure all threads reach checkpoint before proceeding</feature>
            <feature><strong>Cooperative Groups:</strong> Modern thread organization beyond simple block structures</feature>
            <feature><strong>Warp-Level Programming:</strong> Ultra-efficient coordination within 32-thread warps</feature>
            <feature><strong>Dynamic Workload Balancing:</strong> Adaptive thread assignment for irregular problems</feature>
        </features>
        <concepts>
            <concept>
                <title>Thread Cooperation</title>
                <description>Shared memory and synchronization</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🤝 Thread Cooperation Patterns</title>
                <description>Shared memory protocols and data passing mechanisms for safe multi-thread coordination</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🚧 Synchronization Barriers</title>
                <description>__syncthreads() and cooperative groups ensure all threads reach synchronization points together</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🎯 Warp-Level Primitives</title>
                <description>__shfl(), __ballot(), __any() - hardware-accelerated communication within 32-thread warps</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔄 Producer-Consumer Queues</title>
                <description>Lock-free data structures for high-throughput thread communication</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>⚖️ Load Balancing</title>
                <description>Dynamic work distribution algorithms for irregular and unpredictable workloads</description>
            </concept>
        </concepts>
        <applications>
            <application>
                <title>🌊 Stream Processing</title>
                <description>Real-time data pipelines where threads process different stages of streaming data</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🔗 Graph Algorithms</title>
                <description>Complex graph traversal and analysis requiring dynamic thread coordination</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🧠 Neural Network Training</title>
                <description>Multi-stage ML pipelines with data dependencies between processing phases</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🎮 Game Engine Physics</title>
                <description>Complex collision detection and physics simulations with variable computational loads</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🔬 Scientific Simulations</title>
                <description>Multi-physics modeling where different threads handle different physical phenomena</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>💰 High-Frequency Trading</title>
                <description>Financial algorithms requiring ultra-low latency and precise timing coordination</description>
            </application>
        </applications>
        <performance>
            <consideration>Synchronization overhead - minimize barrier usage while maintaining correctness</consideration>
            <consideration>Warp divergence - keep related threads in sync for optimal execution efficiency</consideration>
            <consideration>Memory contention - design data structures to minimize thread conflicts</consideration>
            <consideration>Load imbalance - ensure threads have similar workloads to avoid idle time</consideration>
            <consideration>Occupancy optimization - balance synchronization needs with thread count per block</consideration>
        </performance>
        <importance>
            <why>
                Advanced threading is what separates basic parallel programming from truly sophisticated 
                GPU applications. Real-world problems rarely have perfectly uniform workloads - they 
                involve dependencies, coordination, and complex data flow patterns. Mastering advanced 
                threading enables you to tackle the most challenging parallel programming problems and 
                build applications that can adapt to varying computational demands.
            </why>
            <performance>
                Well-designed thread cooperation can achieve near-linear scaling even with complex 
                dependencies and synchronization requirements. Advanced threading techniques can 
                maintain 90%+ GPU utilization even in applications with irregular workloads, making 
                previously impossible real-time applications practical and efficient.
            </performance>
        </importance>
    </description>
</example>
