<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<example>
    <name>Advanced FFT</name>
    <category>Advanced</category>
    <sourceFile>src/06_advanced_fft/fft_kernels.hip</sourceFile>
    <description>
        <title>Advanced FFT 📊🔄 - The Mathematical Swiss Army Knife of Signal Processing</title>
        <overview>
            This example demonstrates the Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) - one of the most important 
            algorithms in computing, converting signals between time and frequency domains. Like having 
            X-ray vision that reveals hidden frequency patterns in data, FFT powers everything from 
            MP3 compression to wireless communications to earthquake analysis. GPU acceleration makes 
            real-time spectral analysis possible for massive datasets.
        </overview>
        <analogy>
            <strong>Think of it like this:</strong> Imagine analyzing a complex symphony by separating 
            it into individual instrument frequencies - violin, piano, drums, etc. FFT does exactly 
            this for any signal: it takes a time-based waveform and decomposes it into its constituent 
            frequencies. With thousands of GPU threads working in parallel, this musical analysis 
            happens in real-time, enabling everything from noise cancellation to medical imaging.
        </analogy>
        <features>
            <feature><strong>Cooley-Tukey Algorithm:</strong> Optimized divide-and-conquer approach for maximum efficiency</feature>
            <feature><strong>Shared Memory Optimization:</strong> Minimize global memory access through intelligent data staging</feature>
            <feature><strong>Multi-dimensional Support:</strong> Handle 1D, 2D, and 3D FFTs for diverse applications</feature>
            <feature><strong>Precision Options:</strong> Single and double precision for accuracy vs speed trade-offs</feature>
            <feature><strong>Batch Processing:</strong> Process multiple signals simultaneously for maximum throughput</feature>
        </features>
        <concepts>
            <concept>
                <title>FFT Algorithm</title>
                <description>Cooley-Tukey butterfly operations</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🦋 Butterfly Operations</title>
                <description>Core FFT computational pattern - elegant divide-and-conquer that reduces O(n²) to O(n log n)</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🌀 Twiddle Factors</title>
                <description>Pre-computed complex exponentials that encode the trigonometric relationships in FFT</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>⚡ Memory Optimization</title>
                <description>Shared memory staging and bit-reversal addressing for optimal data access patterns</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔄 In-Place Computation</title>
                <description>Minimizing memory usage by performing FFT transformations without additional storage</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>📐 Complex Arithmetic</title>
                <description>Efficient GPU implementations of complex number multiplication and addition</description>
            </concept>
        </concepts>
        <applications>
            <application>
                <title>🎵 Audio Processing</title>
                <description>Real-time audio effects, noise reduction, and music analysis for streaming and production</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>📡 Wireless Communications</title>
                <description>OFDM, LTE, 5G signal processing for mobile networks and satellite communications</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🖼️ Image Processing</title>
                <description>Image filtering, compression, and enhancement in medical imaging and photography</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🔬 Scientific Computing</title>
                <description>Quantum mechanics simulations, crystallography, and computational chemistry</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🌊 Seismic Analysis</title>
                <description>Earthquake monitoring, oil exploration, and geological survey processing</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🏥 Medical Imaging</title>
                <description>MRI reconstruction, CT processing, and ultrasound signal analysis</description>
            </application>
        </applications>
        <performance>
            <consideration>Memory bank conflicts - organize shared memory access to avoid simultaneous bank usage</consideration>
            <consideration>Bit-reversal addressing - efficient permutation algorithms for FFT input/output ordering</consideration>
            <consideration>Complex arithmetic optimization - minimize floating-point operations in butterfly stages</consideration>
            <consideration>Cache efficiency - optimize memory access patterns for different FFT sizes</consideration>
            <consideration>Numerical stability - manage precision loss in large transforms and iterative computations</consideration>
        </performance>
        <importance>
            <why>
                FFT is one of the most important algorithms of the 20th century, enabling the digital 
                revolution in communications, entertainment, and scientific computing. From JPEG compression 
                to WiFi signals to MRI scans, FFT is everywhere. GPU acceleration makes real-time spectral 
                analysis practical, enabling applications that were impossible with CPU-only implementations.
            </why>
            <performance>
                GPU-accelerated FFT can process millions of samples in real-time, enabling applications 
                like real-time spectrum analysis, live audio processing, and immediate medical imaging 
                reconstruction. What once required specialized signal processing hardware can now be 
                done in software on commodity GPUs, democratizing advanced signal processing capabilities.
            </performance>
        </importance>
    </description>
</example>
