<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<example>
    <name>Dynamic Memory</name>
    <category>Advanced</category>
    <sourceFile>src/08_dynamic_memory/dynamic_memory_hip.hip</sourceFile>
    <description>
        <title>Dynamic Memory Management 💾🔄 - Adaptive GPU Applications</title>
        <overview>
            This example demonstrates advanced dynamic memory allocation and management on GPU - 
            essential for applications that don't know their memory requirements at compile time. 
            Like a smart warehouse manager who allocates storage space on demand, this example 
            shows how to efficiently allocate, use, and free GPU memory during program execution 
            without causing memory leaks or fragmentation.
        </overview>
        <analogy>
            <strong>Think of it like this:</strong> Imagine running a library where you don't know 
            how many books people will bring each day. Instead of reserving huge shelves "just in case," 
            you dynamically add and remove shelves as needed. GPU dynamic memory works similarly - 
            allocating exactly what you need, when you need it, and cleaning up efficiently to avoid 
            running out of space.
        </analogy>
        <features>
            <feature><strong>Runtime Memory Allocation:</strong> Allocate GPU memory based on actual data requirements</feature>
            <feature><strong>Memory Pool Management:</strong> Efficient allocation strategies to minimize overhead</feature>
            <feature><strong>Fragmentation Prevention:</strong> Smart allocation patterns to maintain memory efficiency</feature>
            <feature><strong>Error Handling:</strong> Robust handling of allocation failures and memory exhaustion</feature>
            <feature><strong>Performance Monitoring:</strong> Track allocation patterns and memory usage statistics</feature>
        </features>
        <concepts>
            <concept>
                <title>Device Memory</title>
                <description>malloc/free on GPU</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🖥️ GPU Device Memory</title>
                <description>malloc() and free() operations directly on GPU - runtime memory allocation without CPU involvement</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🏊 Memory Pool Management</title>
                <description>Pre-allocated pools of memory chunks to minimize allocation overhead and fragmentation</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🧩 Fragmentation Handling</title>
                <description>Strategies to prevent memory becoming unusably scattered into small, non-contiguous pieces</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>⚡ Allocation Performance</title>
                <description>Understanding the overhead costs and timing considerations of dynamic allocation</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔒 Thread Safety</title>
                <description>Ensuring safe memory operations when multiple threads allocate and free memory simultaneously</description>
            </concept>
        </concepts>
        <applications>
            <application>
                <title>🧠 Adaptive Machine Learning</title>
                <description>Neural networks that grow and shrink based on data complexity and training requirements</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>📊 Dynamic Data Structures</title>
                <description>GPU-based hash tables, trees, and graphs that resize based on input data</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🎮 Game Engine Systems</title>
                <description>Runtime object allocation for particles, effects, and dynamic world elements</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🔬 Scientific Simulations</title>
                <description>Adaptive mesh refinement and particle systems that change resolution during computation</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>💡 Stream Processing</title>
                <description>Real-time applications that process varying amounts of data without knowing sizes beforehand</description>
            </application>
        </applications>
        <performance>
            <consideration>Allocation overhead - dynamic allocation is slower than static, so minimize frequency</consideration>
            <consideration>Memory fragmentation - use consistent allocation sizes when possible</consideration>
            <consideration>Thread divergence - avoid having different threads in a warp allocate different amounts</consideration>
            <consideration>Memory coalescing - ensure allocated memory can still be accessed efficiently</consideration>
            <consideration>Error recovery - always check allocation success and have fallback strategies</consideration>
        </performance>
        <importance>
            <why>
                Dynamic memory management is crucial for building flexible, scalable GPU applications. 
                Many real-world problems don't have fixed memory requirements - data sizes vary, 
                algorithms adapt, and systems need to respond to changing conditions. Understanding 
                dynamic GPU memory allocation enables you to build applications that are both 
                efficient and adaptable to real-world conditions.
            </why>
            <performance>
                Proper dynamic memory management can make the difference between an application 
                that runs out of memory and one that scales gracefully. While dynamic allocation 
                has overhead, smart pooling and caching strategies can achieve near-static performance 
                while maintaining the flexibility needed for modern GPU computing applications.
            </performance>
        </importance>
    </description>
</example>
