<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<example>
    <name>Matrix Multiplication</name>
    <category>Basic</category>
    <sourceFile>src/02_matrix_multiplication/matrix_mul.cu</sourceFile>
    <description>
        <title>Matrix Multiplication 🧮✖️ - The Workhorse of Modern Computing</title>
        <overview>
            This example demonstrates optimized matrix multiplication using GPU shared memory - 
            the fundamental operation behind machine learning, computer graphics, and scientific computing. 
            Like organizing an assembly line where workers efficiently share tools, this example shows 
            how thousands of GPU threads collaborate to multiply massive matrices at lightning speed.
        </overview>
        <analogy>
            <strong>Think of it like this:</strong> Imagine a giant spreadsheet multiplication factory. 
            Instead of one person multiplying row×column by hand, you have 1000 teams working simultaneously. 
            Each team shares a whiteboard (shared memory) to temporarily store the numbers they're working 
            with, dramatically reducing trips to the main filing cabinet (global memory).
        </analogy>
        <features>
            <feature><strong>Shared Memory Optimization:</strong> Fast on-chip memory reduces global memory accesses by 100x</feature>
            <feature><strong>2D Thread Organization:</strong> Natural mapping of threads to matrix elements</feature>
            <feature><strong>Memory Coalescing:</strong> Optimized access patterns for maximum bandwidth</feature>
            <feature><strong>Tiled Algorithm:</strong> Divide-and-conquer approach for large matrices</feature>
            <feature><strong>Performance Analysis:</strong> Compare CPU vs GPU execution with timing measurements</feature>
        </features>
        <concepts>
            <concept>
                <title>🚀 Shared Memory</title>
                <description>Ultra-fast on-chip memory shared by threads in a block - 100x faster than global memory</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🚀 Thread Block 2D Layout</title>
                <description>Organizing threads in a 2D grid that naturally maps to matrix structure</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🚀 Memory Tiling</title>
                <description>Breaking large matrices into smaller tiles that fit in shared memory</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🚀 Synchronization Barriers</title>
                <description>__syncthreads() ensures all threads finish loading data before computation begins</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🚀 Memory Coalescing</title>
                <description>Threads access consecutive memory locations for maximum bandwidth efficiency</description>
            </concept>
        </concepts>
        <applications>
            <application>
                <title>🤖 Machine Learning</title>
                <description>Neural network training - every layer forward/backward pass involves matrix multiplication</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🎮 Computer Graphics</title>
                <description>3D transformations, lighting calculations, and shader operations rely on matrix math</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🔬 Scientific Computing</title>
                <description>Solving systems of equations, finite element analysis, and numerical simulations</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>💰 Financial Modeling</title>
                <description>Risk analysis, portfolio optimization, and derivative pricing calculations</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🧬 Bioinformatics</title>
                <description>Sequence alignment, protein folding simulations, and genomic data analysis</description>
            </application>
        </applications>
        <performance>
            <consideration>Shared memory bank conflicts - ensure threads don't access the same memory bank simultaneously</consideration>
            <consideration>Optimal tile size - balance between shared memory usage and arithmetic intensity</consideration>
            <consideration>Thread divergence - all threads in a warp should follow the same execution path</consideration>
            <consideration>Memory access patterns - coalesced access can improve bandwidth by 10x</consideration>
            <consideration>Occupancy optimization - maximize threads per multiprocessor for better utilization</consideration>
        </performance>
        <importance>
            <why>
                Matrix multiplication is the backbone of modern computing. It's the most important operation 
                in machine learning (every neural network layer), computer graphics (every 3D transformation), 
                and scientific computing (solving virtually every numerical problem). Understanding optimized 
                matrix multiplication on GPU teaches you the fundamental performance principles that apply 
                to all high-performance computing.
            </why>
            <performance>
                A well-optimized GPU matrix multiplication can achieve 1000x speedup over naive CPU code. 
                Modern GPUs can perform trillions of floating-point operations per second (TFLOPS), 
                making real-time machine learning and scientific simulations possible. This is why 
                every major AI breakthrough relies on GPU acceleration.
            </performance>
        </importance>
    </description>
</example>
