<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<example>
    <name>Monte Carlo</name>
    <category>Basic</category>
    <sourceFile>src/05_monte_carlo/monte_carlo.cu</sourceFile>
    <description>
        <title>Monte Carlo Simulation 🎯🎲 - Statistical Magic with Millions of Random Experiments</title>
        <overview>
            This example demonstrates Monte Carlo methods - using random sampling to solve complex 
            mathematical problems that would be impossible to compute directly. Like throwing millions 
            of darts at a dartboard to calculate π, or flipping millions of coins to predict market 
            behavior, Monte Carlo methods harness the power of probability and massive parallelism 
            to tackle problems in finance, physics, and machine learning.
        </overview>
        <analogy>
            <strong>Think of it like this:</strong> Imagine trying to find the area of an irregularly 
            shaped lake. Instead of complex mathematics, you throw thousands of pebbles randomly 
            over the area. By counting how many land in the lake versus on land, you can estimate 
            the lake's area! GPU Monte Carlo works the same way - millions of "digital pebbles" 
            (random samples) are thrown simultaneously by different threads, giving incredibly 
            accurate results through the power of statistics.
        </analogy>
        <features>
            <feature><strong>Massive Random Sampling:</strong> Generate millions of random numbers in parallel using cuRAND</feature>
            <feature><strong>Statistical Convergence:</strong> Watch accuracy improve as sample size increases</feature>
            <feature><strong>Multiple Applications:</strong> Calculate π, integrate complex functions, and model uncertainty</feature>
            <feature><strong>Performance Analysis:</strong> Compare GPU vs CPU for statistical computing workloads</feature>
            <feature><strong>Quality Assessment:</strong> Analyze randomness quality and convergence properties</feature>
        </features>
        <concepts>
            <concept>
                <title>Random Number Generation</title>
                <description>cuRAND library usage</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>Monte Carlo Methods</title>
                <description>Statistical sampling</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🎲 Parallel Random Number Generation</title>
                <description>cuRAND library generates millions of high-quality random numbers simultaneously across GPU threads</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>📊 Statistical Sampling Theory</title>
                <description>Law of large numbers ensures accuracy improves with more samples - the foundation of Monte Carlo</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔄 Parallel Reduction</title>
                <description>Efficiently combining millions of individual sample results into final statistical estimates</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🎯 Convergence Analysis</title>
                <description>Understanding how quickly and accurately results approach the true value</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>⚖️ Numerical Precision</title>
                <description>Managing floating-point accuracy when accumulating millions of small contributions</description>
            </concept>
        </concepts>
        <applications>
            <application>
                <title>💰 Financial Risk Analysis</title>
                <description>Option pricing, portfolio optimization, and risk assessment for banks and investment firms</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🌡️ Climate and Weather Modeling</title>
                <description>Uncertainty quantification in weather prediction and climate change projections</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🎮 Game AI and Procedural Generation</title>
                <description>Creating realistic randomness in games, from terrain generation to AI decision-making</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🧬 Molecular Dynamics</title>
                <description>Simulating particle interactions in chemistry and materials science research</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🚀 Engineering Design</title>
                <description>Uncertainty analysis in aerospace, automotive, and structural engineering projects</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🔬 Scientific Research</title>
                <description>Complex integration, Bayesian inference, and hypothesis testing across disciplines</description>
            </application>
        </applications>
        <performance>
            <consideration>Random number quality - ensure statistical independence and uniform distribution</consideration>
            <consideration>Convergence rate - more samples give better accuracy but require more computation</consideration>
            <consideration>Memory access patterns - organize computations to maximize memory throughput</consideration>
            <consideration>Numerical stability - prevent accumulation of floating-point errors in large sums</consideration>
            <consideration>Load balancing - ensure all threads perform similar amounts of work</consideration>
        </performance>
        <importance>
            <why>
                Monte Carlo methods are essential when exact solutions are impossible or impractical. 
                Many real-world problems - from financial risk to weather prediction to drug design - 
                involve too many variables for direct calculation. Monte Carlo transforms these 
                impossible problems into manageable statistical sampling, and GPU acceleration 
                makes previously impractical computations run in real-time.
            </why>
            <performance>
                GPU Monte Carlo can perform millions of simulations per second, enabling real-time 
                financial risk assessment, interactive scientific modeling, and complex optimization. 
                What once took hours on CPUs now completes in seconds, revolutionizing fields that 
                depend on statistical analysis and uncertainty quantification.
            </performance>
        </importance>
    </description>
</example>
