<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<example>
    <name>N-Body Simulation</name>
    <category>Advanced</category>
    <sourceFile>src/11_nbody_simulation/nbody_hip.hip</sourceFile>
    <description>
        <title>N-Body Simulation 🌌⭐ - Simulating the Universe's Gravitational Dance</title>
        <overview>
            This example demonstrates N-body gravitational simulation - modeling the complex interactions 
            between thousands of celestial bodies like stars, planets, and galaxies. Like watching the 
            cosmic ballet where every particle influences every other through gravitational forces, 
            this simulation showcases GPU's incredible power for physics modeling, revealing how 
            thousands of objects can interact simultaneously in real-time.
        </overview>
        <analogy>
            <strong>Think of it like this:</strong> Imagine a cosmic dance floor with thousands of dancers, 
            where each dancer is attracted to every other dancer with a force that depends on their 
            masses and distances. As they move, the gravitational forces constantly change, creating 
            complex orbital patterns, collisions, and emergent behaviors. With GPU acceleration, 
            we can simulate this intricate dance with astronomical numbers of particles in real-time.
        </analogy>
        <features>
            <feature><strong>Barnes-Hut Algorithm:</strong> Reduces O(n²) complexity to O(n log n) for massive simulations</feature>
            <feature><strong>Spatial Partitioning:</strong> Octree data structures for efficient neighbor finding</feature>
            <feature><strong>Force Optimization:</strong> Shared memory and approximation techniques for performance</feature>
            <feature><strong>Multi-GPU Scaling:</strong> Distribute massive simulations across multiple GPUs</feature>
            <feature><strong>Visualization Ready:</strong> Real-time position updates for interactive display</feature>
        </features>
        <concepts>
            <concept>
                <title>N-Body Physics</title>
                <description>Gravitational force calculations</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🌍 Gravitational Physics</title>
                <description>Newton's law of gravitation applied to thousands of interacting bodies simultaneously</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🌳 Barnes-Hut Tree Algorithm</title>
                <description>Hierarchical space subdivision that reduces computational complexity from O(n²) to O(n log n)</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🧊 Octree Spatial Partitioning</title>
                <description>3D space division into octants for efficient neighbor searches and force approximations</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>⚡ Force Approximation</title>
                <description>Multipole expansion techniques to approximate distant forces while maintaining accuracy</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔄 Numerical Integration</title>
                <description>Time-stepping algorithms like Verlet and Runge-Kutta for stable orbital mechanics</description>
            </concept>
        </concepts>
        <applications>
            <application>
                <title>🌌 Astrophysics Research</title>
                <description>Galaxy formation, stellar cluster evolution, and dark matter distribution studies</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🚀 Space Mission Planning</title>
                <description>Trajectory optimization, gravitational assists, and multi-body orbital mechanics</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🧬 Molecular Dynamics</title>
                <description>Protein folding simulations, drug design, and materials science at the atomic level</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🎮 Game Physics</title>
                <description>Realistic particle systems, destruction effects, and large-scale physics simulations</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🏭 Fluid Dynamics</title>
                <description>Smoothed particle hydrodynamics for engineering and environmental modeling</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🔬 Plasma Physics</title>
                <description>Fusion research, magnetosphere modeling, and high-energy particle interactions</description>
            </application>
        </applications>
        <performance>
            <consideration>Load balancing - ensure particles are distributed evenly across GPU threads</consideration>
            <consideration>Memory coalescing - organize particle data for optimal memory access patterns</consideration>
            <consideration>Tree traversal efficiency - minimize divergent execution paths in spatial queries</consideration>
            <consideration>Numerical stability - maintain precision in force calculations over long time periods</consideration>
            <consideration>Scalability - design algorithms that work efficiently from hundreds to millions of particles</consideration>
        </performance>
        <importance>
            <why>
                N-body simulation is the foundation of computational physics and astronomy. It's how we 
                understand galaxy formation, design space missions, and study everything from planetary 
                rings to dark matter. The same techniques apply to molecular dynamics, materials science, 
                and any system where many objects interact through forces. GPU acceleration has revolutionized 
                our ability to simulate complex systems that were previously impossible to model.
            </why>
            <performance>
                Modern GPU N-body simulations can handle millions of particles in real-time, enabling 
                interactive exploration of cosmic phenomena and real-time physics in games and simulations. 
                What once required supercomputers now runs on desktop GPUs, democratizing access to 
                sophisticated physics modeling and enabling new discoveries in science and engineering.
            </performance>
        </importance>
    </description>
</example>
