<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<example>
    <name>Vector Addition</name>
    <category>Basic</category>
    <sourceFile>src/01_vector_addition/vector_addition.cu</sourceFile>
    <description>
        <title>Vector Addition 🧮 - The "Hello World" of GPU Programming</title>
        <overview>
            This example demonstrates the fundamental concept of parallel vector addition on GPU - 
            adding two arrays element by element using thousands of GPU cores simultaneously. 
            It's like having an army of calculators working together, each adding corresponding 
            numbers from two lists at the same time.
        </overview>
        <analogy>
            <strong>Think of it like this:</strong> Imagine you have two phone books and need to add 
            the page numbers. Instead of one person doing it sequentially, you give each page to a 
            different person - suddenly 1000 people are adding numbers simultaneously!
        </analogy>
        <features>
            <feature><strong>Parallel Processing:</strong> Thousands of GPU cores working simultaneously</feature>
            <feature><strong>Memory Management:</strong> Efficient data transfer between CPU and GPU</feature>
            <feature><strong>Performance Measurement:</strong> Compare GPU vs CPU execution times</feature>
            <feature><strong>Result Verification:</strong> Ensure parallel computation matches sequential results</feature>
        </features>
        <concepts>
            <concept>
                <title>🔧 Memory Management</title>
                <description>cudaMalloc, cudaMemcpy, cudaFree - the essential trio for GPU memory operations</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔧 Kernel Launch</title>
                <description>&lt;&lt;&lt;grid, block&gt;&gt;&gt; syntax - how to tell the GPU "run this code on N threads"</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔧 Thread Indexing</title>
                <description>threadIdx, blockIdx, blockDim - each thread knows its unique ID and position</description>
            </concept>
            <concept>
                <title>🔧 Synchronization</title>
                <description>cudaDeviceSynchronize - wait for all GPU work to complete before proceeding</description>
            </concept>
        </concepts>
        <applications>
            <application>
                <title>🚀 Foundation for All GPU Operations</title>
                <description>Every GPU algorithm builds on these basic parallel principles</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🚀 Data Processing Pipelines</title>
                <description>Massive datasets processed in parallel for analytics and machine learning</description>
            </application>
            <application>
                <title>🚀 Scientific Computing</title>
                <description>Mathematical computations across large arrays in physics and engineering</description>
            </application>
        </applications>
        <performance>
            <consideration>Memory coalescing - accessing GPU memory efficiently in sequential patterns</consideration>
            <consideration>Optimal grid and block sizing - balance between parallelism and resource usage</consideration>
            <consideration>Minimizing CPU-GPU memory transfers - the biggest performance bottleneck</consideration>
        </performance>
        <importance>
            <why>
                Vector addition is the foundation of GPU programming. Master this, and you understand 
                how parallel computing works. It's simple enough to grasp quickly but demonstrates 
                all the core concepts you'll use in complex applications.
            </why>
            <performance>
                A modern GPU can add millions of numbers in the time it takes a CPU to add thousands. 
                This 100x+ speedup is why GPUs revolutionized machine learning, scientific computing, 
                and cryptocurrency mining.
            </performance>
        </importance>
    </description>
</example>
